Abdulwahab O. Jimoh

Frontend Developer | React | Nextjs



omoniyi.success@gmail.com

****+234(818) 802-6726 / +234(704) 367-8597



linkedin.com/in/wabjay

Phttp://www.abdulwahabjimoh.netlify.app

Summary

I'm a front-end developer, I have prioritized refining customer satisfaction in approaches to a host of projects I have overseen which has in turn endeared me to clients. Having devoted my time to science and technology, I recognize the quest of man to use the web as a tool for immense possibilities and I am keen to help actualize the vision.

I surely realize the need for continuous updates, as it is the only constant in the field of technology to provide the best website development experience to my customers.

Skills

Problem Solving • Written Communication • Redux.js • Front-End Development • JavaScript Frameworks • Tailwind CSS • React.js • Next.js • JavaScript • Redux Thunk

Experience



Ethco Group Limited

Frontend Developer

Aug 2022 - Present

Building the landing pages, admin web app for helping Ethnic and Independent convenience store owners.

- Converted the Ethco figma landing page to pixel perfect implemented code with full responsiveness using plain HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Worked on Airtable API to receive data from forms.
- Worked on the Ethco admin portal using next.js and ant design forms.
- Used redux for the state management and consumed the API created from the backend.

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript, Nextis, React-redux, Airtable, AntDesign, Formspree

Ownerfi

Frontend Web Developer

Sep 2022 - Oct 2022 (2 months)

Developed project with reactjs, built a step form and manage data state with context api. Implement ReactQuill for rich text editor and address autocomplete using google place autocomplete. Used firebase for database stage and user authentication.

Technologies used: Reactjs, Context API, ReactQuill, Firebase, Google place API

Techtank Labs

Website Developer

Jul 2022 - Aug 2022 (2 months)

Designed the landing pages with reactjs and implemented form designs to email integration with EmailJs.

Technologies used: Reactjs, EmailJs

Ayrem

Frontend Web Developer

May 2020 - Dec 2021 (1 year 8 months)

Ayrem is a safe and trustworthy way for africans to purchase crypto , gift card and data plans conveniently at unbeatable rates

Some of my achievements at Ayrem are:

- Convert the Ayrem figma landing page to pixel perfect implemented code with full responsiveness.
- Worked on the Ayrem web app design of over 50 pages and converted it using plain HTML, CSS and JavaScript code.
- Consumed the API created backend and implemented it on the Ayrem web app.
- Designed and implemented the Ayrem admin backend office using HTML, CSS and JavaScript.
- Strategize with the team to implement features to make the website more engaging to the users.

Technologies used: HTML, CSS, JavaScript

Education

Kwara state polytechnic

National Diploma, Computer Science

2012 - 2014

Licenses & Certifications

National Diploma - Kwara State Polytechnic



Jobberman Soft-skills Training - Jobberman Nigeria



G Fundamental of Digital Marketing - Google